Vipin Gopinath UI Engineer

Address 8-35/5, Plot No 42

New Hemanagar, Hyderabad-39,India

Phone +91 8977357398

Email vipin.vipin.q498@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipin-gopinath7/

https://github.com/viping7

https://www.facebook.com/vipin.gopinath.92

Skills

Front-end Development

HTML/CSS/SCSS

★★★☆ Expert

Javascript

★★☆☆ Intermediate

Angular Js / Angular

★ ★ ☆ ☆ Intermediate

jQuery

★★☆☆ Intermediate

Back-end Development

PHP

★ ★ ☆ ☆ ☆ Beginner

Node Js / Express Js

★★☆☆☆ Beginner

Database

MySQL

★★☆☆ Intermediate

MongoDB

★ ★ ☆ ☆ Beginner

About Me

I am 22 year old UI Engineer from kerala, currently living in Hyderabad, India. I have a passion for creating beautiful, intuitive, and highly crafted solutions combining a considered approach with emerging technologies. I like going through new stuffs which includes tech and tv series during my freetime.

Work Experience

F1 Studioz

UI Engineer, July 2016 - Present

Responsible for converting awesome designs into efficient and high performing web applications with easily managable code and effortless integration.

Works include client side development of rich javascript applications by leveraging power of technologies like Angular JS, Angular, React, jQuery, HTML 5, SASS and build tools like gulp.

Worked closely with designers and backend developers to deliver pixel perfect and efficient web apps and sites.

Intech Solutions

Frontend Developer, April 2016 - June 2016

Was Responsible for designing and coding static websites for promoting Bulk SMS Service all across India.

Worked on various technologies like HTML5, CSS, jQuery etc to build responsive and appealing websites.

Projects

Angular bits

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, Angular 2

Role - Lead developer

An Angular 2 based web application that helps create beautiful & responsive layouts using structured and validated HTML and SCSS.

Well structured pick and use appproach to make the process of development easier

Media Vision MVRITS

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

Role - Lead Developer

A web application to increase participation and intelligibilty for meetings by providing features like language interpretation, polling service etc.

Customized the components of metronics theme to build user friendly interface with rich features.

Chakrview

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

Role - Lead Developer

A social networking site that allows users to connect with each other of their community and to create their family tree.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering (2012-2016)

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University I St. Mary's College of Engg. and Tech

10th and 10+2 (2010-2012)

Kendriya Vidyalaya Ottapalam, Kerala